Kotschnig, Walter Maria; Papers ger053
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications of Walter M. Kotschnig, 1923-1971; 7; 86 folders
  - "Demand and Supply in the Learned Professions", 1938 February 14 (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 25)
  - "The National Mind - English, French and German. By Michael Demiashkevich". Review, 1939 March (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 26)
  - "The Learned Class in Germany Today", 1939 March 22-1939 March 25 (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 27)
  - "Art and the Child", 1939 October (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 28)
  - "Educating the Elite in Europe", 1939 October (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 29)
  - "Educational Changes in Germany, 1936-1939", 1939 October (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 30)
  - "The International Bureau of University Statistics", 1940 January (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 31)
  - "Toward Building a New World Order", 1940 April 12 (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 32)
  - "The Fault Is Ours", 1941 January (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 33)
  - "Education in the Balance", 1941 September 23 (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 34)
  - "Comparative Education. By Henry L. Smith". Review, 1941 October (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 35)
  - "Haben Sie gut geschlafen ...?", 1941 December 27 (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 36)
  - The Educational Philosophy of National Socialism. By George Frederick Kneller". Review, 1942 January (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 37)
  - "Problems of Education after the War", 1942 April (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 38)
  - "Educational Reconstruction", 1942 June (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 39)
  - "Presuppositions of World Peace", 1942 June (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 40)
  - "Relief" (excerpt from Slaves Need No Leaders), 1942 October (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 41)
  - "Presuppositions of World Peace", 1942 October 12-1942 November 23 (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 42)
  - "Post-War Education in the United States", 1942 December (Box 14 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 43)
  - "Tells America of Job Abroad. Educator Asserts We Cannot Impose Our Methods on War-Wrecked Schools", 1942 December 13 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 1)
  - "The Messianic Complex". Written with I. L. Kandel, 1943 February 06 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 2)
  - "Slaves or Freemen?", 1943 February 25 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 3)
  - "The School in Colonial Expansion. The Italianization of African Natives, by Roland R. DeMarco". Review, 1943 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 4)
  - "Reconstructing Education in Europe after the War", 1943 May (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 5)
  - "The Time Is Now", 1943 May (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 6)
  - "Education for a World Rebuilt", 1943 October (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 7)
  - "Re-Education Of People Of Nazi And Occupied Lands Is Big Peace Task", 1943 December 22 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 8)
  - "V. Education and Imperialism", 1944 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 9)
  - "VI. Education for a New World Order", 1944 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 10)
  - "World Order Through Education", 1944 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 11)
  - "The Professions - A Gaze into the Crystal Ball", 1944 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 12)
    Page proofs. Apr. 14, 1944; article, Apr. 25, 1944.
  - "Toward an IOECD: Some Major Issues Involved", 1944 July (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 13)
  - "Realism in Educational Reconstruction", 1944 September (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 14)
  - "Education and the United Nations", 1945 March (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 15)
  - "ECOSOC 1948: A Review and Forecast", 1949 March (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 16)
  - "The United Nations - Road to Economic and Social Progress", 1949 Summer (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 17)
  - "Forced Labor Conditions in Communist-Dominated Countries", 1950 September 25 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 18)
  - "Forced Labor. Who are the Real Criminals?", 1951 March 15 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 19)
  - "Investigation of Forced Labor Conditions in U.S.S.R. and Satellites Urged", 1951 April 02 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 20)
  - "What Was Oatis' Crime? An Honest Newspaperman doing an Honest and Conscientious Job", 1951 August 15 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 21)
  - "Economic and Social Foundations of the United Nations", 1951 October (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 22)
  - "U.S. Presents Evidence of Forced Labor in U.S.S.R", 1952 July 14 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 23)
  - "World Social Situation. The Way of the Free and the Way of the Slave", 1952 July 14 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 24)
  - "Human Welfare: A Practical Objective", 1952 July 28 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 25)
  - "Coordinating the Programs of the United Nations", 1955 July 19 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 26)
  - "The Economic Situation in Asia". Written with Howard P. Jones, 1956 March 05 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 27)
  - "The United States Government, Non-Governmental Organizations and the United Nations", 1956 April (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 28)
  - "The U.N. Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East", 1957 May 13 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 29)
  - "Review of Economic and Social Programs and Activities of the United Nations and Specialized Agencies", 1957 September 09 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 30)
  - "International Aid for Underdeveloped Countries", 1958 February 24 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 31)
  - "Social Action: An Instrument of Foreign Policy", 1958 May 11 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 32)
  - "United Nations Economic and Social Council". Written with Christopher H. Phillips, 1958 September 01 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 33)
  - "Planning Economic and Social Development", 1959 September 23 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 34)
  - Economic and Social Council Committee on Programme Appraisals. "Programme Appraisal 1959-1964. Consolidated Report". First draft, 1960 January 23 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 35)
  - Economic and Social Council Committee on Programme Appraisals. "Programme Appraisal 1959-1964. Consolidated Report". Working paper No. 3/Rev. 1, 1960 March 28 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 36)
  - "Social Development and Foreign Policy", 1960 May (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 37)
  - "African Development", 1963 February 22 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 38)
  - "Health - Key to Development", 1966 Fall (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 39)
  - "The United Nations as an Instrument of Economic and Social Development", 1968 Winter (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 40)
  - "Natural Disasters: Agenda for Action", 1968 October 30 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 41)
  - "Facts and Ideas on Industrialization", 1968 December 01 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 42)
  - "Science and Technology in the United Nations", 1971 January 11 (Box 15 (7-Publications of Walter M. ), Folder 43)
- Photographs, ca. 1920-1972; 1944-1972; 8; over 1000 photographs
  The photograph collection, with the exception of a number of professional portrait photographs of Kotschnig, dates predominately from the years 1944-1972 and contains numerous photographs of official United Nations gatherings and especially sessions of the United Nations Economic and Social Council. Included in the collection are approximately 385 informal snapshots, many with U.N. colleagues and dignitaries. Many of the photographs were identified by Kotschnig on the verso of the photo.
  - Studio portrait photo of Foss Shanahan, President of ECOSOC, Undated (Box 16A (8-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Studio portrait photos of Walter M. Kotschnig, 1920s-1970s; 15 photos (Box 16A (8-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Poland, 1944-1946; 67 photos (Box 16B (8-Photographs), Folder 1)
    Photos of war-destroyed areas of Poland.
  - UN Commission to Study War Devastated Areas. Photographs of Commission in Poland, photographed by Jerzy Baranowski, Film Polski, Undated; 43 photos (Box 16B (8-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - UN Commission to Study War Devastated Areas. Photographs of Commission in Czechoslovakia, photographed by Ceskoslovenská tisková kancelá, Undated; 33 photos (Box 16B (8-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - Official photographs, Department of State, United Nations, 1945-1964; 8.6 (Box 16C (8-Photographs))
    - UNESCO Prep Commission. London, 1945-1946; 2 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 1)
    - 1947 August, 2 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 2)
    - UN Conference on Freedom of Information. Geneva, 1948; 8 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 3)
    - Youth Looks at the UN radio program. San Francisco, 1949 April 02; 1 photo (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 4)
    - International Labor Organization meeting. Geneva, 1949; 9 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 5)
    - Burma, 1952; 10 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 6)
    - 16th ECOSOC. Geneva, 1953; 31 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 7)
    - Canadian party, 1953 December; 2 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 8)
    - Montevideo conference, 1954; 1 photo (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 9)
    - New York, 1954; 9 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 10)
    - New York, 1955; 5 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 11)
    - UNESCO. Buenos Aires, 1956; 8 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 12)
    - 21st ECOSOC. New York, 1956 April-1956 May; 7 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 13)
    - ECOSOC. Geneva, 1956; 8 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 14)
    - Slavery Conference. Geneva, 1956; 4 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 15)
    - Dept. of State, 1957; 2 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 16)
    - 23rd ECOSOC. New York, 1957 April; 4 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 17)
    - ECOSOC. New York, 1960 April; 3 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 18)
    - 31st ECOSOC. New York, 1961 April; 1 photo (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 19)
    - UN FAO Conference. Rome, 1962 February; 3 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 20)
    - UNESCO, Istanbul, 1962 September; 5 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 21)
    - Department of State, 1962; 3 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 22)
    - FAO Conference, 1963; 2 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 23)
    - UNESCO, 1964; 2 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 24)
    - ECOSOC. Geneva, 1964 July-1964 August; 10 photos (Box 16C (8-Photographs), Folder 25)
  - Official photographs, Department of State, United Nations, 1965-1972; 8.7 (Box 17A (8-Photographs))
    - 1965, Undated; 1 photo (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 1)
    - ECOSOC. Geneva, 1965 Summer; 3 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 2)
    - Department of State, 1966; 1 photo (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 3)
    - UNIDO. Athens, Greece, 1967 December; 21 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 4)
    - 1968 February, 1 photo (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 5)
    - Department of State, 1968; 1 photo (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 6)
    - ECOSOC, 1968; 12 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 7)
    - ECOSOC, 1969; 3 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 8)
    - FAO. Rome, 1969 November; 4 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 9)
    - Department of State, 1970; 10 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 10)
    - ECOSOC. Geneva, 1970 Summer; 2 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 11)
    - UN Narcotics Commission, Special Session. Geneva, 1970 September 28-1970 October 03; 3 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 12)
    - ECOSOC, 1970s; 13 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 13)
    - Undated, 31 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 14)
    - Undated, 1 photo (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 15)
      Photographer: David Parlet, Baltimore, MD.
    - Undated, 11 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 16)
      Photographer: J. Cadoux, Geneva.
    - Undated, 13 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 17)
      Photographer: J. G. Cadoux, Geneva.
    - Undated (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 18)
    - Undated, 19 photos (Box 17A (8-Photographs), Folder 19)
      Photographer: Leo Rosenthal, New York.
  - Photographs of UN ECAFE (Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East) and ECA (Economic Commission for Africa) Conferences, 1956-1965; 8.8 (Box 17B (8-Photographs))
    - ECAFE Conference. Bangalore, India, 1956; 43 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 1)
    - ECAFE Conference. Bangkok, 1957; 33 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 2)
    - ECA Conference. Addis Ababa, 1958; 14 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 3)
    - ECAFE Conference. Kuala Lumpur, 1958; 30 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 4)
    - ECAFE Conference. Bangkok, 1959 September; 7 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 5)
    - ECAFE Conference. Bangkok, 1962 January-1962 February; 17 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 6)
    - ECA Conference. Leopoldville, 1963; 4 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 7)
    - ECAFE Conference. New Zealand, 1965; 12 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 8)
    - Bangkok, 1965 April; 8 photos (Box 17B (8-Photographs), Folder 9)
  - Snapshot photos, including personal photographs, informal gatherings of Kotschnig with other U.N. and Dept. of State personnel, many identified on verso of photograph, Undated; ca. 385 photos (Box 17C (8-Photographs))
- Subject files, 1945-1972; 9; 81 folders
  The subject files contain general materials pertaining to the United Nations, as well as specific materials pertaining to sessions of the Economic and Social Council, and the United Nations Commission on Narcotic Drugs.
  - League of Nations, 1938-1939 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 1)
  - Comments and Proposed Amendments Concerning the Dumbarton Oaks Proposals, 1945 May 07 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 2)
    Kotschnig's personal copy, with annotations.
  - Charter of the United Nations. Report to the President on the Results of the San Francisco Conference by the Chairman of the United States Delegation, The Secretary of State, 1945 June 16 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 3)
    Kotschnig's personal copy, autographed by the members of the United States Delegation.
  - "Recommendations with Respect to Specific Articles formulated by the United States Commission on Human Rights at its Second Session in Geneva in December 1947", Undated (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 4)
  - ECAFE, Kuala Lumpur, 1958 March (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 5)
  - Personnel efficiency ratings, 1960s (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 6)
  - ECAFE clippings, 1965 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 7)
  - International Symposium on Industrial Development (UNIDO), Athens, 1967 November 29-1967 December 19 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 8)
  - International Organizations - Reorganization Management Survey, 1970 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 9)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council. Publications, 1971-1972 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 10)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council. Publications, 1973-1975 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 11)
  - UNESCO, Undated; Clippings, notes (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 12)
  - United Nations General Assembly. Publications, Undated (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 13)
  - United Nations Seventh Special Session of the General Assembly, 1-12 September 1975 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 14)
  - United Nations Seventh Special Session of the General Assembly, 1-16 September 1975; Clippings (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 15)
  - United Nations Seventh Special Session. Notes, Undated (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 16)
  - Second United Nations Development Decade. Publications, notes, 1975 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 17)
  - Adhoc Committee on the Restructuring of the Economic and Social Sectors of the United Nations System, 1975-1977 (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 18)
  - United Nations, Undated; Clippings, notes (Box 18 (9-Subject files), Folder 19)
  - Convention on Narcotic Drugs, 1961 March 30-1961 August 01 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 1)
  - U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations Hearings on accession by the US to the Single Convention on Narcotics Drugs 1961, 1967 April 27 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 2)
  - World Plan of Action Against Drug Addiction, 1967-1970 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 3)
  - Special Session of UN Commission on Narcotic Drugs, Geneva, 1970 September 28-1970 October 02 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 4)
  - "Report of the United Nations Project Preparation Mission to Thailand in the Field of Narcotics Control, 1 October-9 December 1970", Undated (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 5)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control, 1970 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 6)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control, 1971 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 7)
  - Consultative Mission to East and Central Europe, 1971-1972 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 8)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Thailand, 1971 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 9)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Thailand, 1972 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 10)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Thailand, 1973 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 11)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Thailand, background materials, Undated (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 12)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control, 1972 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 13)
  - Reorganization of Narcotics Activities, 1972 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 14)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control. Summary Report, 1972 December (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 15)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Afghanistan, 1972-1973 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 16)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Burma, 1972-1973 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 17)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Lebanon, 1972 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 18)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control, 1973 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 19)
  - United Nations Fund for Drug Abuse Control - Southeast Asia, 1973 (Box 19 (9-Subject files), Folder 20)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council, Commission on Narcotic Drugs, 1970 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 1)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council, Commission on Narcotic Drugs, 1971 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 2)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council, Commission on Narcotic Drugs, 1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 3)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council, Commission on Narcotic Drugs, 1973 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 4)
  - United Nations Economic and Social Council, Commission on Narcotic Drugs, 1974 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 5)
  - United Nations General Assembly, Action on Narcotics, 1970 October-1970 November (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 6)
  - United Nations General Assembly, Action on Narcotics, 1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 7)
  - Staffing of the Division of Narcotic Drugs, 1971 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 8)
  - United Nations Conference for the Adoption of a Protocol on Psychotropic Substances, Vienna, 1971 January 11-1971 February 21 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 9)
  - Amendments to Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs 1961, 1971 March-1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 10)
  - World Health Organization, 1971-1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 11)
  - UNESCO Program on Drug Education, 1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 12)
  - Consultants' Meeting, Geneva, 1972 March 06-1972 March 16 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 13)
  - United Nations Division of Narcotic Drugs, Provisional Program of Operation, 1972-1973 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 14)
  - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 15)
  - Ad Hoc Inter-Agency Meeting on Narcotics Questions, London, 1972 March (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 16)
  - Ad Hoc Inter-Agency Meeting on Narcotics Questions, Geneva, 24-26 July 1972 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 17)
  - Consultants Meeting, Geneva, 1972 November (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 18)
  - Inter-Agency Committee for Co-ordination of Activities in the Field of Drug Abuse Control, Geneva, 17-19 September 1973 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 19)
  - International Narcotics Control Board (INCB), Undated (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 20)
  - United Nations Division of Narcotic Drugs Information Letter, 1971-1974 (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 21)
  - United Nations films, Undated (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 22)
  - U.S. government publications on narcotics, Undated (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous reports on narcotics issues, Undated (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous materials, clippings on narcotics issues, Undated (Box 20 (9-Subject files), Folder 25)
  - Austrian Bulletin in the United States, 1941 (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 1)
  - Department of State materials, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 2)
  - Diplomats / Diplomacy, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 3)
  - Educational Reconstruction, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 4)
  - Foreign Affairs article, 1974-1975 (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 5)
  - Helms, Jessie (Helms Amendment), Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 6)
  - Human Rights. Notes, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 7)
  - International Labor Office (ILO), Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 8)
  - International NGO Conference on Disarmament, Geneva, 1978 February 27-1978 March 02 (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 9)
  - International Office of Education / Post-War Education, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 10)
  - Kissinger, Henry, Undated; clippings (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 11)
  - Kissinger, Henry. Speeches, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 12)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, U.S. Senator, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 13)
  - Popes, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 14)
  - U.S. participation in the United Nations, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 15)
  - U.S. policies (controversial) / Lobbies, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials, Undated (Box 21 (9-Subject files), Folder 17)
- Pamphlets, 1922-1978; 10; 136 items
  The pamphlets in the series focus on topics such as narcotics, the United Nations and educational issues. Thirty pamphlets cover topics relating to the International Student Service, including annual reports and conference publications.
  - Pamphlets dealing with European Student Relief, International Student Service, World Student Service Fund, and World Student Relief, 1922-1945; 10.1 (Box 22 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 1-30)
    - Minutes of the Turnov Conference. Held under the auspices of the European Student Relief, April 8th-16th 1922, Turnov, Czechoslovakia (Box 22 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 1)
    - Protokoll der Konferenz in Parad. Abgehalten unter dem Schutze der Europäischen Studentenhilfe, 14.-24. Juni 1923, Parad, Ungarn (Box 22 (10-Pamphlets), Folder 2)